Finding Aid for the Reverend Eugene Smathers Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Reverend Eugene Smathers Papers
1932-1968
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0398
45.65 linear_feet
Eugene Smathers Biographical Sketch
Dec. 4, 1907 Born in Bath County, Kentucky
1929 A.B. Transylvania College
1932 B.D.Louisville Presbyterian Seminary
1942 Married Louoile Boydston of Berrysville, Ark.
1932-68 Pastor of Calvary Presbyterian Church of Big Lick, Tn. near Crossville.
1937-38 Warren H. Wilson House of Health Constructed
1940 Author of "I Work in the Cumberlands", Fellowship of Southern Churchmen
1940-41 Interracial and interfaith work camps held at Big Lick
1942-45 Special Lecturer in rural life and leadership at the School of Religion, Vanderbilt University
1942 "Primer for Friends of the Soil", Friends of the Soil
1943 "Study Guide for Use with Bailey's Holy Earth",
1944 "Stewards of the Soil", Friends of the Soil
1949 D.D., Honorary Degree, Centre College, Ky.
1950 Rural Paster of the Year for Tennessee
President of Natl. Presbyterian Town and Country Fellowship
Chairman of Committee on Natl. Missions, Presbytery of Cumberland Mtn., and of the Synod of Mid-South
Chairman, Cuaberland County Rural Health Council
ca. 1950 - 59 Member of Bd. of Directors of Uplands Sanatorium
1959 Member of Exec. Comm. of Natl. Presby. Rural Fellowship
1967 Chairman of Bd. of Cumberland Co. Farmers Cooperative
May, 1967 Elected Moderator by the General Aaseably of the United Presbyterian Church, U.S.A.
Aug. 18, 1968 Died, Big Lick, Tn.
Table of Contents
The Smathers Collection is divided into two series: a regular, and a miscellaneous series. The "regular" series includes Boxes 1-39, and contains the following: 1) Smathers' incoming correspondence; 2) Smathers' outgoing correspondence; and 3) Smathers' sermons and sermon materials.
The miscellaneous series, Miscellaneous Boxes 1-22, includes the following:
1) various materials collected by Smathers, and listed according to subject
2) articles, papers and pamphlets by Smathers, plus publications about Smathers and Big Lick
3) Board of National Missions Monthly Reports by Smathers and by others, and miscellaneous reports on various projects
4) pamphlets collected by Eugene Smathers, arranged by publisher
- Regular Series
  - Incoming Correspondence
    - Aalfs - Barr (Box 1)
    - Barrett - Britton (Box 2)
    - Broady - Chappel (Box 3)
    - Cheek - Dahl (Box 4)
    - Dallas - Drake (Box 5)
    - Draughn - Fite (Box 6)
    - Flanagin - Greenway, C.T. (1938) (Box 7)
    - Greenway, C.T. (1939) - Hamilton, C. (Box 8)
    - Hamilton, H. - Holloway (Box 9)
    - Holmes - Keener (Box 10)
    - Keesecker, William F. - Kronk (Box 11)
    - Kuester - Malmo (Box 12)
    - Maloney - McVeigh (Box 13)
    - McVoy - Morton (Box 14)
    - Moser - Pfeufer (Box 15)
    - Pfuetze - Randolph, H.S. (1954) (Box 16)
    - Randolph, H.S. (1955-1963) - Rodgers (Box 17)
    - Rodriguez - Sherratt (Box 18)
    - Sherrill - Stover (Box 19)
    - Stowers - Urich (Box 20)
    - Vail - Wilson, E. (Box 21)
    - Wilson - Zeufeldt (Box 22)
    - First name only, fragments, initials, illegible, unsigned (Box 22)
    - Incoming Correspondence - Miscellaneous, Includes book orders and inquiries, consumers book cooperative, Lowther Co., machinery and supply orders and inquiries, orders for smathers' pamphlets, and for Christmas greens. (Box 23)
      - Books - Orders And inquiries (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Consumer's Book Cooperatives, July 14, 1941-1943 (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - Leather Company (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Machinery and Supply Orders and Inquiries A-B (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - Machinery and Supply Orders and Inquiries C-E (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Machinery and Supply Orders and Inquiries F-K (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - Machinery and Supply Orders and Inquiries L (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - Machinery and Supply Orders and Inquiries W (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Orders for "Stewards of the Soil" and "Primer" (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - Orders for Christmas Greens (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Outgoing Correspondence, 1932-1968; undated
    - 1932-1942 (Box 24)
    - 1943-1947 (Box 25)
    - 1948-June 1950 (Box 26)
    - July 1950-1953 (Box 27)
    - 1954-1957 (Box 28)
    - 1958-1968; undated (Box 29)
  - Sermons
    - Sermons 1929-39 plus 1930's undated. (Box 30)
    - Sermons, 1940-1945 (Box 31)
    - Sermons, 1946-1951 (Box 32)
    - Sermons, 1952-1956 (Box 33)
    - Sermons, 1957-1960 (Box 34)
    - Sermons, 1961-65 (Box 35)
    - Sermons 1966-67 plus undated sermons (Box 36)
    - Sermons for Thanksgiving and Passion Week (Box 37)
      Also sermon notes, ideas and miscellaneous printed naterial from sermons.
  - Addenda to Smathers' Incoming Correspondence in boxes 1-22 (Box 38-39)
    - Ackley, Frederic B., 1947; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Albert, Aadrew, 1942-62; (38) letters (Box 38)
    - Alridge, D.M., 1960; (2) letters (Box 38)
      Council of the Southern Mtns., Inc.
    - Allen, A.J., 1944; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Allred, C.E., 1943; (1) letters (Box 38)
      Univ. of Tenn.
    - Almon, Martha D., 1942; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Amis, Will, 1946; (5) letters (Box 38)
    - Anderson, E.A., 1940; (1) letters (Box 38)
      Tusculum College
    - Anderson, Harrison Ray, 1946; (1) letters (Box 38)
      General Assembly - Presby. Ch.
    - Anderson, W.B (Mrs.), 1945; (2) letters (Box 38)
    - Archer, Terry, 1948; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Argie, Robert D., 1956; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Auernheimer, Florence, 1950; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Austin, Richard C., 1965; (1) letters (Box 38)
      Georgetown Presby. Ch.
    - Bailey, Jean, 1953-54; (2) letters (Box 38)
      Dept. of Public Welfare (Tn.)
    - Baker, James W., 1945-46; (2) letters (Box 38)
    - Bannerman, Arthur M., 1941; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Barr, F. K. (MRS.), 1951; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Barrett, Hall, 1958; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Bell, J. Leslie, 1954; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Benton, John Keith, 1944; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Bigger, John D., 1944; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Bigham, Wlm., 1948; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Bishop, S/C., 1939-46; (2) letters (Box 38)
      Chronicle Publishing Co.
    - Blake, Eugene Carson, 1953; (1) letters (Box 38)
      Gen. Assembly - Presby. Ch.
    - Blood, Bob, 1944; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Boardman, Douglas S., 1961; (1) letters (Box 38)
      Forestry Representative
    - Bockman, L.D., 1940; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Boggs, Wade H., 1944; (1) letters (Box 38)
      Christian Educ. and Ministerial Relief
    - Bolin, Luke, 1944; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Bollinger, H.D., 1944; (1) letters (Box 38)
      Meth. Bd. of Educ.
    - Boyd, Eraest H., 1945-46; (12) letters (Box 38)
    - Boyd, Joe Dan, 1968; (1) letters (Box 38)
      Farm Journal
    - Brookhart, Mary, 1950; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Brown, Kate C., 1939; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Brown, Ward (Mrs.), 1946; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Burns, J.T., 1944; (1) letters (Box 38)
      Huntswille Larger Parish
    - Burroughs, George W., 1946; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Burton, James D., 1938-39; (3) letters (Box 38)
    - Caldwell, Frank H., 1953; (1) letters (Box 38)
      The Louisville Presby. Seminary
    - Carothers, J. Edwin, 1950; (1) letters (Box 38)
      Alpine Forest Reserve Forester
    - Carr, James M., 1941-54; (3) letters (Box 38)
      Town and Country Church Dept.
    - Case, Ralph T., 1948; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Cathey, C.E., 1940-45; (7) letters (Box 38)
      Bd. of Christian Educ. - Presby. Ch.
    - Chappel, Merlyn A., 1945-51; (8) letters (Box 38)
      Bd. of National Missions
    - Cavert, Samuel McCrea, 1951; (1) letters (Box 38)
      Natl. Council of the Ch. of Christ
    - Clark, Ernest L., 1956; (1) letters (Box 38)
      The Ky.-Tn. St. Farm Paper Unit
    - Cleaveland, W.M. (Mrs.), (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Coapman, Verne E., 1944-59; (15) letters (Box 38)
    - Cobb, Alice, 1961; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Cody, E. Frank, 1948; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Coffman, Edw., Jr., 1944; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Coafort, Richard. O., 1945-47; (4) letters (Box 38)
    - Cofort, Robert F., 1961; (3) letters (Box 38)
    - Covington, B.W., 1946-55; (4) letters (Box 38)
    - Cowan, Foster, 1949-53; (2) letters (Box 38)
      Tenn. Dept. of Conservation
    - Cowan, T.B. (Scotty), 1937-57; (25) letters (Box 38)
      Fellowship of Southern Churchmen
    - Cowley, R.H., 1938; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Coye, Elmer, 1958; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Coyle, F.A. (Mrs.), 1947; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Cox, A.E., 1959; (2) letters (Box 38)
      Delta Foundation
    - Cox, D.E., 1958; (1) letters (Box 38)
      First Presby. Ch. - Paw Paw, Ill.
    - Cox, Robert and Rachel, 1940; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Cox, Samuel (Mrs.), 1945; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Coxen, Burl, 1945-46; (2) letters (Box 38)
    - Crab Orchard Stone Co., 1958; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Crabtree, Homer, 1945-49; (5) letters (Box 38)
      Natl. Farmers Union
    - Craig, A.K., 1953; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Craig, Rena, 1957; (4) letters (Box 38)
      Union Theological Sellinary
    - Cranwell, T.G., 1968; (1) letters (Box 38)
      Bledsoe Memorial Hoap.
    - Crary, Steve, 1959; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Crawford, Chas. S., 1967; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Crawford, J.C., 1940; (1) letters (Box 38)
      Scarritt College
    - Creeger, M.J., 1944; (1) letters (Box 38)
      Christian Commission (Caap and Defence Communities)
    - Creighton, J.W., 1960; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Crenshaw, George, 1943; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Creps, John E., Jr., 1958; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Cressey, Paul F., 1942; (1) letters (Box 38)
      Wheaton College
    - Crewton, John, n.d.; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Cribb, Aubrey, 1946; (1) letters (Box 38)
      Ohio Council of Churches
    - Criswell, Jack, 1951; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Crivella, Aline, 1967; (2) letters (Box 38)
    - Crockett, F.S., 1946-48; (3) letters (Box 38)
      American Medical Assoc.
    - Crockett, S.R., 1966; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Croft, Helen M., 1957; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Cromwell, Owena, n.d.; (1) letters (Box 38)
      Synodioal Society of Mid-South
    - Crooks, Robt. H., Jr., 1952; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Cross, Frank Moore, 1948; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Cross, Helen, 1961; (5) letters (Box 38)
    - Crossno, R.G., 1954; (1) letters (Box 38)
      City of Norris, Tenn.
    - Crossrllle Chrilnicle, 1956; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Crossrllle Hardware, 1949; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Crouch, Ada Metcalfe, 1946-52; (5) letters (Box 38)
      Uplands
    - Crouch, Chas. O., 1949; (2) letters (Box 38)
    - Crowder, Howard. V., 1956; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Crowder, Robt., 1957; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Csordas, Gabor, 1952; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Cultural Services, Inc., n.d.; (1) letters (Box 38)
    - Culver, Betty, 1967; (1) letters (Box 38)
      United Churchwoman of Tenn.
    - Culver, Roland - May, Hugh L. (Box 38)
    - McAfee, John A - York, William (Box 39)
- Miscellaneous Series, Boxes Misc. 1-9: Various materials collected by Smathers, arranged by subject. Box Misc. 10: Articles and papers by Smathers, arranged chronologically, 1930-68, plus no dates; Pamphlets by Smathers; publications about Smathers and Big Lick, 1921-68, plus no dates; Board of National Missions - Monthly Reports by Smathers, 1932-68, plus miscellaneous reports by Smathers; Board of National Missions - Monthly Reports by others, 1944-54. Box Misc. 11: Board of National Missions - Monthly Reports by others, 1955-68, and no dates; Board of National Missions reports on various projects; also Board miscellaneous reports. Boxes Misc. 11-22: Pamphlets collected by Eugene Smathers; pamphlet fragments and no publishers; also two photographs (fragments etc. and photographs - Box 22)
  - Adult Education (Box Misc. 1, Folder 1)
  - Adult Education - Conf. of Southern Mtn. Workers (Box Misc. 1, Folder 2)
  - Agricultural Societies - Public and Private (Box Misc. 1, Folder 3)
  - Agriculture - General (Box Misc. 1, Folder 4)
  - Allardt (Box Misc. 1, Folder 5)
  - Alpine, Tn. (Alpine Center, The Cottage, Alpine Pariah) (Box Misc. 1, Folder 6)
  - Amusements, Recreation, Games (Box Misc. 1, Folder 7)
  - Appalachia (A Report from S. Appalachia by Philip H. Young) (Box Misc. 1, Folder 7.5)
  - Applications for Bd. of Natl. Missions Aid, 1944-46 (Box Misc. 1, Folder 8)
  - Same, 1947-50 (Box Misc. 1, Folder 8.5)
  - Same, 1951-53 (Box Misc. 1, Folder 9)
  - Same, 1955 (Box Misc. 1, Folder 10)
  - Same, 1956-57 (Box Misc. 1, Folder 11)
  - Same 1959-62 and n.d. (Box Misc. 1, Folder 12)
  - Applications to Bd. of Natl. Missions - Mrs. Dorothy Nelson (Box Misc. 1, Folder 13)
  - Applications of Candidates for the Ministry, and Reference Reports (Box Misc. 1, Folder 13.5)
  - Baptism (Box Misc. 1, Folder 14)
  - Bible (Box Misc. 1, Folder 15)
  - Bible Studies (Box Misc. 1, Folder 16)
  - Bible Study Outlines - Holograph and Typed Notes (Box Misc. 1, Folder 17)
  - Bibliographies (Box Misc. 1, Folder 18)
  - Big Lick (Box Misc. 1, Folder 19)
  - Big Lick Community Organization & Area Project - Soil Conservation (Box Misc. 1, Folder 20)
  - Same (Box Misc. 1, Folder 21)
  - Big Lick Farmer's Association (Box Misc. 1, Folder 22)
  - Biographical Information, Eugene Smathers (Box Misc. 1, Folder 23)
  - Board of National Missions, 1937-1960 (Box Misc. 1, Folder 24)
  - Same, 1966-1967 (Box Misc. 1, Folder 25)
  - Board of Natl. Missions - Docket Sheets, 1946-47 (Box Misc. 1, Folder 26)
  - Same, 1948-53 (Box Misc. 1, Folder 27)
  - Board of Natl. Missions Speakers, 1958 (Box Misc. 1, Folder 28)
  - Book Renews - Religious (Box Misc. 1, Folder 29)
  - Boy's Clubs, 1967 (Box Misc. 1, Folder 30)
  - Building Fund Campaign (Box Misc. 1, Folder 31)
  - Building Plans for Seals Church (Box Misc. 1, Folder 32)
  - Business Papers, Invoices, Miscellaneous (Box Misc. 1, Folder 33)
  - Business Papers of Smathers (Financial Receipts, Bills, Misc.) (Box Misc. 1, Folder 34)
  - Cabinet File - (Library) (Box Misc. 1, Folder 35)
  - Calvary Church (Box Misc. 1, Folder 36)
  - Calvary Church Buildings (Box Misc. 1, Folder 37)
  - Calvary Fellowship - Parish Newspaper, 1942-44 (Box Misc. 1, Folder 38)
  - Charcoal (Box Misc. 1, Folder 39)
  - Chattanooga Presbytery (Box Misc. 1, Folder 40)
  - Children and Youth (Box Misc. 1, Folder 41)
  - Christian Doctrines (Box Misc. 1, Folder 42)
  - Christian Education (Box Misc. 1, Folder 43)
  - Same (Box Misc. 1, Folder 44)
  - Christian Education (Box Misc. 2, Folder 45)
  - Same (Box Misc. 2, Folder 46)
  - Christian Education - Church School (Box Misc. 2, Folder 47)
  - Christian Education - Organization and Administration of (Box Misc. 2, Folder 48)
  - Christian Education - Principles of - Smathers' Seminary Work (Box Misc. 2, Folder 49)
  - Christian Faith (Box Misc. 2, Folder 49.5)
  - Christian Marriage and Family (Box Misc. 2, Folder 50)
  - Same (Box Misc. 2, Folder 51)
  - Christian Rural Fellowship (Box Misc. 2, Folder 52)
  - Christian Rural Fellowship Bulletin #1-55 (1935-Oct., 1940) (Box Misc. 2, Folder 53)
  - Same - #56-100 (Nov., 1940-Feb., 1945) (Box Misc. 2, Folder 54)
  - Same - #101-140 (Mar., 1945-Feb., 1949) (Box Misc. 2, Folder 55)
  - Same - #150-188 (Feb., 1950-Dec., 1953) (Box Misc. 2, Folder 56)
  - Same - #191-244 (Mar., 1954-Spring, 1966) (Box Misc. 2, Folder 57)
  - Christian Rural Fellowship Study Conference (Box Misc. 2, Folder 58)
  - Same - Notes on Discussions (Box Misc. 2, Folder 59)
  - Christian Rural Overseas Program (Box Misc. 2, Folder 60)
  - Christian Theology and Rural Life (Box Misc. 2, Folder 60.5)
  - Christian Year (Box Misc. 2, Folder 61)
  - Christmas - 1940's, 1950's, 1960's (Box Misc. 2, Folder 62)
  - Christmas Calendar Lists (Box Misc. 2, Folder 63)
  - Christmas Greens Project, 1958 (Box Misc. 2, Folder 64)
  - Christmas Greetings Received, 1965-66 (Box Misc. 2, Folder 65)
  - Church (General) (Box Misc. 2, Folder 66)
  - Chrueh Administration (Box Misc. 2, Folder 67)
  - Church and Agricultural Policy (Box Misc. 2, Folder 68)
  - Church and Community (Box Misc. 2, Folder 69)
  - Church and Race (Box Misc. 2, Folder 70)
  - Church and Sects (Box Misc. 2, Folder 71)
  - Church and Segregation (Box Misc. 2, Folder 72)
  - Church Bulletins - Misc. (Box Misc. 2, Folder 73)
  - Church Finance (Box Misc. 2, Folder 74)
  - Church Groups, 1963, 1964, 1967, 1968 (Box Misc. 2, Folder 75)
  - Church History - Holograph and Typed Notes (Box Misc. 2, Folder 76)
  - Same (Box Misc. 2, Folder 77)
  - Church Kitchen Plans and Materials, 1960 (Box Misc. 2, Folder 78)
  - Churches Sponsoring Eugene Smathers (Box Misc. 2, Folder 79)
  - Church Leadership (Box Misc. 2, Folder 79.5)
  - Class Material (Box Misc. 2, Folder 80)
  - Class Material - Rural Studies (Box Misc. 2, Folder 81)
  - Same (Box Misc. 2, Folder 82)
  - Class Material - Smathers (Box Misc. 2, Folder 83)
  - Class Material - Smathers - Religious Education (Box Misc. 3, Folder 84)
  - Class Notes - College (Box Misc. 3, Folder 85)
  - Class Outlines - Copy of (Box Misc. 3, Folder 86)
  - College Notes and Syllabi (Box Misc. 3, Folder 87)
  - College Students (Box Misc. 3, Folder 88)
  - Comfort, Richard and John Matthew (Box Misc. 3, Folder 89)
  - Committee of Southern Churchmen (Box Misc. 3, Folder 90)
  - Committee on National Missions, Presbytery of Cumberland Mtns. - Reports, etc. (Box Misc. 3, Folder 91)
  - Same *** Also see folders #242, 243, 244, National Missions Comm - Presby. of Cumberland Mtns. (Box Misc. 3, Folder 92)
  - Community Sawmill Project + Community Shop Association - Holograph Notes, etc. (Box Misc. 3, Folder 93)
  - Conferences, Various - Information on, Pamphlets (Box Misc. 3, Folder 94)
  - Conservation - Soil and Water (Box Misc. 3, Folder 95)
  - Correspondence Material from, 1945, 1958, 1962 (Box Misc. 3, Folder 96)
  - Correspondence with Women's Groups, 1953 - Material from (Box Misc. 3, Folder 97)
  - Council of Southern Mtns. - Cumberland Co. Chapter, 1964-66 (Box Misc. 3, Folder 98)
  - Council of Southern Mtns. - Spiritual Life Committee (Box Misc. 3, Folder 99)
  - Council of Southern Mtn. Workers (Box Misc. 3, Folder 100)
  - County Planning Group (Box Misc. 3, Folder 101)
  - County Planning Group - Health and Welfare (Box Misc. 3, Folder 102)
  - Courses of Study (Smathers' Notes included) (Box Misc. 3, Folder 103)
  - Courses Taught by Smathers (Box Misc. 3, Folder 104)
  - Credit Union Information (Box Misc. 3, Folder 105)
  - Cumberland County (Box Misc. 3, Folder 106)
  - Cumberland County Council (Box Misc. 3, Folder 107)
  - Cumberland Co. Cultural and Community Foundation (Box Misc. 3, Folder 108)
  - Cumberland Co. Ministerial Assoc, 1960-67 (Box Misc. 3, Folder 109)
  - Cumberland County Planning Group (Box Misc. 3, Folder 110)
  - Cumberland Co. Woodland Development, 1957-60 (Box Misc. 3, Folder 111)
  - Cumberland Farmers Cooperative, 1963-67 (Box Misc. 3, Folder 112)
  - Cumberland Mtn. Presbytery, 1926-39 (Box Misc. 3, Folder 113)
  - Same, 1940-1949 (Box Misc. 3, Folder 114)
  - Same, 1950-1956 (Box Misc. 3, Folder 115)
  - Same, 1957-1959 (Box Misc. 3, Folder 115.5)
  - Same, 1960-1963 + n.d.'s (Box Misc. 3, Folder 116)
  - Cumberland Presbyterian Ministers' Conference, 1965 (Box Misc. 3, Folder 117)
  - Dale Hollow Parish, 1948-59 + n.d.'s (Box Misc. 3, Folder 118)
  - Department of Town and Country (Box Misc. 3, Folder 119)
  - Devotional - Personal and Religious Life and Growth (Box Misc. 3, Folder 119.5)
  - Disciples' Workshop on Southern Mtns, 1960-64 (Box Misc. 3, Folder 120)
  - Discipleship Studies - Holograph Notes (Box Misc. 3, Folder 121)
  - Dockets and Grants, 1952-59 (Box Misc. 3, Folder 122)
  - Economics (Box Misc. 3, Folder 123)
  - Ecumenical Training Center, Stony Point, N.Y., Feb. 18-21, 1960 (Box Misc. 3, Folder 124)
  - Ecumenical Training Center Group, Aug., 20 - Sept., 1, 1960 (Box Misc. 3, Folder 125)
  - Education (Box Misc. 3, Folder 126)
  - Ethics (Box Misc. 3, Folder 127)
  - Evangelism (Box Misc. 3, Folder 128)
  - Exegesis of Epistle to Romans (Box Misc. 3, Folder 129)
  - The Family and Its Christian Fulfillment - Wisers (Box Misc. 4, Folder 129.5)
  - Family Life - Miscellaneous Material (Box Misc. 4, Folder 130)
  - Same (Box Misc. 4, Folder 131)
  - Farm Equipment (Box Misc. 4, Folder 132)
  - Farm Issues (Box Misc. 4, Folder 133)
  - Same (Box Misc. 4, Folder 134)
  - Fellowship of Southern Churchmen, 1938-41 (Box Misc. 4, Folder 135)
  - Same, 1945-1949 (Box Misc. 4, Folder 136)
  - Fellowship of Southern Churchmen, 1950-55 (Box Misc. 4, Folder 137)
  - Same, 1956-60 (Box Misc. 4, Folder 138)
  - Fellowship of Southern Churchmen Newsletter (Box Misc. 4, Folder 139)
  - Fellowship of Southern Churchmen - Proposed Retreat (Box Misc. 4, Folder 140)
  - Same - Maps and Surveys (of Retreat Area) (Box Misc. 4, Folder 141)
  - Same - Proposed Retreat - Swannanoa, N.C. (Box Misc. 4, Folder 142)
  - Fellowship of Southern Churchmen - Rural Reconstruction Commission, 1946-47 (Box Misc. 4, Folder 143)
  - Field Survey Material - Board of Natl. Missions (Box Misc. 4, Folder 144)
  - Financial Papers, Misc. regarding Presbyterian Church (Box Misc. 4, Folder 145)
  - Forrestry (Box Misc. 4, Folder 146)
  - Same (Box Misc. 4, Folder 147)
  - Freedom - Danger to the Preservation of (Box Misc. 4, Folder 148)
  - Friends of the Soil (Box Misc. 4, Folder 149)
  - Geese Raising (Box Misc. 4, Folder 150)
  - General Assembly, May 20-28, 1952 (Box Misc. 4, Folder 151)
  - Same, 1967 (Box Misc. 4, Folder 152)
  - Same, 1967 (Box Misc. 4, Folder 153)
  - Same - 1967-68 + n.d.'s (Box Misc. 4, Folder 154)
  - Same - Committee Reports and Minutes, 1966 (Box Misc. 4, Folder 155)
  - Same, 1967 (Box Misc. 4, Folder 156)
  - Same, 1967 (Box Misc. 4, Folder 157)
  - Same, 1967 (Box Misc. 4, Folder 158)
  - Same, 1967-68 (Box Misc. 4, Folder 159)
  - General Assembly Communion Service, May 16, 1968 (Box Misc. 4, Folder 160)
  - General Assembly Material for Talks (Box Misc. 4, Folder 161)
  - General Literature (Box Misc. 4, Folder 162)
  - Genessee, V. - Presbyterian Trip, Oct. 10-24, 1965 (Box Misc. 4, Folder 163)
  - Gospels (Box Misc. 4, Folder 164)
  - Hardison, E.K. Seed Co. (Box Misc. 4, Folder 165)
  - Health (Box Misc. 4, Folder 166)
  - Health Center Construction, 1937-38 (Box Misc. 4, Folder 167)
  - History (Box Misc. 4, Folder 168)
  - Holly Orders, 1953-56 (Box Misc. 4, Folder 169)
  - "Holy Earth" - A Study Guide - Working Materials (Box Misc. 4, Folder 170)
  - Home Economics (Box Misc. 4, Folder 171)
  - Home Missions Congress, Jan., 24-27, 1950 (Box Misc. 5, Folder 172)
  - House of Health (Box Misc. 5, Folder 173)
  - House of Health - Nursing Program - Vouchers, Reports (Box Misc. 5, Folder 174)
  - Houston, Wlm. and Vocational Rehabilitation (Box Misc. 5, Folder 175)
  - Hull-York Lakeland Project, 1967 (Box Misc. 5, Folder 176)
  - Indiana School (Box Misc. 5, Folder 177)
  - Information Service (Box Misc. 5, Folder 178)
  - Information with Church Groups, 1955 (Box Misc. 5, Folder 179)
  - Interpretation - Work of Church (Box Misc. 5, Folder 180)
  - Interseminary Movement, 1947 (Box Misc. 5, Folder 181)
  - Jewett College, Construction of 1939, Broady Memorial Fund (Box Misc. 5, Folder 182)
  - Labor (Box Misc. 5, Folder 183)
  - Land Tenure Conference - Cumberland Plateau (Box Misc. 5, Folder 184)
  - Language Notes - Hebrew? - Holograph (Box Misc. 5, Folder 185)
  - Lecture Material for Negro Rural Pastor’s Institutes, 1944 (Box Misc. 5, Folder 186)
  - Lectures by Others (Box Misc. 5, Folder 187)
  - Lectures by Eugene Smathers - and Bibliography by Patricia Smathers Konstam (Box Misc. 5, Folder 188)
  - Lectures by Eugene Smathers (Box Misc. 5, Folder 189)
  - Same (Box Misc. 5, Folder 190)